Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today Marco we're
talking about some
very special places, right?
That's right, today we're going
to talk about the famous list of the
seven wonders of the world so
you've probably heard about this before.
We're not going to tell you what this means
quite yet. Take a listen to today's dialogue and
when we come back we'll talk a little bit more
about what these wonders are and where they are.
Have you seen this news article? Apparently
an organization has made a list to
name the new seven wonders of the world
and people could vote for them online.
Wow, that's really interesting, so who won?
Well, the Great Wall of
China, the Taj Mahal in India.
I've been there, it really is an
amazing work of architecture and art.
The entire complex is made of
white marble and in the interior
of the tomb the walls are
covered with gyms and emeralds.
Cool. Also amongst the
winners is Petra in Jordan, Machu
Picchu in Peru and the
pyramid in Chichinica in Mexico.
Wait a minute, it also says
that the Christ Redeemer
statue in Brazil in the
Colosseum in Rome are wonders.
I would love to go
to Italy and see the
Colosseum, stay in the
middle like a gladiator.
Well, let's see if we can
find some cheap airfare
and we can go towards
the end of the year.
Good idea.
All right, we're back, so
let's talk about these very
interesting places all over the
world now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the set phrase for this Marco
is the seven wonders of the world.
Now the key here is the word
wonder, what is a wonder?
Right, a wonder is something
very amazing, incredible.
It's something that's beyond
your imagination almost.
That's right, you can't even imagine
how man or how someone created it.
And so wonderful is a
similar word that's an adjective,
something that's just
great, fantastic is wonderful.
A wonder is something very, very
special and here we have seven of them.
That's right, so it's a list
basically that you can you
can see even online about
these wonders all over the world.
And they're so special because they
are amazing works of art and architecture.
And starting off with
one of the most famous
ones is in China, it's
the great wall of China.
I think what's special about
this I've heard is that when
astronauts are in space,
it's so long and so distinct.
They can actually see the great wall.
Yeah, that's what
I've heard as well, it's a
very long wall, thousands
of kilometers long.
That's right, and it goes east to west
all across the northern border of China.
That's right, so it's a very big wall.
And what's interesting about
it is that it was built such a long
time ago and that the techniques
used to make it were very special.
That's right, and sometimes
you might hear us talk
about the great wall instead
of the great wall of China.
And so that's just a
hint, it's easy to say
great wall, you can say
them both ways though.
Exactly.
Now moving west towards
India, we have another very
amazing work of architecture,
it's called the Taj Mahal.
Now the Taj Mahal is in North
India in a city called Agra, and it's very
special because it's massive, it's
very big, and it's all white marble.
That's right, and it's interesting
because this place that
Taj Mahal is not really a
temple, it was actually a tomb.
All right, now that's an interesting
word to look at, a tomb, a
tomb is a place where we bury
someone, you know, after someone dies.
Maybe if you have a lot of
money or very rich, you want to put
that body in a very special sacred
place and that's called a tomb.
That's right, so this is
actually what the Taj Mahal is.
Now, we saw in the
dialogue that the entire
complex of the Taj Mahal
is made of white marble.
So when we talk about the
entire complex, what do we mean?
Well, complex here is a noun, you might have
heard it in other situations where it's an
adjective, it means something different, but here
a complex means many buildings together, right?
So, you can say the Taj Mahal is one building, but
the Taj Mahal complex maybe has four or five buildings
together, so a side temple and a gate house, and
so we say a complex is a grouping of buildings.
That's right, very good, so now let's
move on, let's take a look at language
takeaway part two, and let's continue
talking about these wonders of the world.
Now, the top of our list in
language takeaway part two is
actually a place I would love
to go to. I've never been there.
It's in Jordan, which is a country in
the Middle East, and it's called Petra.
Petra, that's right, this
is actually a city, but
it's also known as the
Lost City of Petra, right?
That's right, and what's unique about
this city is that the city is built, it's
carved out of stone in this cliff, so it's
not just pieces of stone put together.
It's actually inside the rocks.
Exactly, so it's very famous, you've
probably seen it in movies like
Indiana Jones, there's a big part of
the scenes that go on inside Petra.
Very special place, and again, very unique.
Now, the next site is actually
very far away in South America, and
again, it's ancient and very
intricate, it's called Machu Picchu.
That's right, so this
is in one of those very
old cities that are
actually in ruins now,
and the interesting
thing about it is that
it's very high up in
like a little mountain.
And those mountains there,
those are the Andes, right?
That's right, so Machu Picchu
also a very famous place,
many visitors from all over
the world go there as well,
and another main attraction
around the world are
the pyramids, so we have
some pyramids in Egypt,
I think those are the
most well-known ones.
That's right, the
pyramids in Egypt, like
the Pyramid of Giza,
are very big structures.
I mean, they're huge, and they
were built thousands of years
ago, but they're still here
because they were built so well.
But they're also very
famous pyramids like the one
we heard about today
in the dialogue in Mexico.
That's right, it's a little bit different
though, because the pyramids, as
we most of us know them, they're
very smooth on the sides, you would say.
Yeah, you can't climb
on them really, right?
Well, this one in Mexico
actually has kind of like steps,
so it's a different type of pyramid,
but the shape is very similar.
All right, so the pyramids
here are in a place
called Chichen Itza, you
might have heard of that,
and we have another
place though, which is also
in South America in
the city of Rio de Janeiro.
Now, this one is actually a statue, right?
That's right, it's called the Christ
Redeemer, it's a very big statue, very famous,
you've seen it maybe in pictures.
It's a statue of Jesus with his arms open.
Now, the word
Redeemer, a Redeemer is a
person, someone who does
something who redeems.
What does it mean
to be a Redeemer?
Well, a Redeemer is a person
that saves souls, for example,
so if you redeem yourself, you're
redeem yourself of your sins, maybe.
Well, yeah, you're taking value back,
right? And so, in the case of Jesus,
he is taking away the
sins of the world and his
Redeemer, you know,
that's why his arms are out,
he's redeeming all people. And that's the
idea, I think, behind the Christ Redeemer.
The verb Redeem, like
you can use it in everyday
life if you take a coupon
and you redeem it.
That means you, yeah,
you collect the value.
You collect the value,
right? So you can use it
actually this word in
everyday life. You can.
And moving on now
towards Europe, we have the
famous Colosseum. Ooh,
now I love this one, I've
actually been there, and I
know you have two, recently.
But this is a circular,
like a round stadium.
So it's a place where
you play sports.
Well, you did. It's from,
you know, thousands
of years ago, the
Roman Empire, and it's in
good shape, I would
say, you can still see it.
Yeah, so it's generally
called the Colosseum,
although a Colosseum,
as we know it now, can
also be the same thing,
right? A structure where
sports or activities are played. Basically,
yeah, Colosseum is an old stadium.
But the Colosseum, like you said, is
definitely the Colosseum in Rome. That's right.
And we've probably seen
movies of ancient Rome
where sports or
activities were taken place,
specifically gladiator
fights. So that's our word,
they're gladiator.
Yeah, that's right.
So gladiator is actually a
person. And a gladiator was a man
who thousands of years
ago during the Roman Empire
would fight, maybe
other men or animals, and
he had to fight to stay
alive. So that was his
profession, basically,
to be a gladiator.
So now as you are a boxer
back then, you were a gladiator.
Yeah, and there are
actually some very famous
movies about
gladiators, like the movie
Gladiator with Russell
Crowe. So it's a pretty
common word these
days. That's right. Okay,
so let's take a break. Let's listen to our
dialogue again, and we'll be back in a bit.
Have you seen this news
article? Apparently an
organization has made
a list to name the new
Seven Wonders of the
World, and people could vote
for them online. Wow,
that's really interesting.
So who won? Well, the Great Wall of China,
the Taj Mahal in India. I've been there.
It really is an amazing
work of architecture and art.
The entire complex is
made of white marble,
and in the interior of the tomb, the walls
are covered with gyms and emeralds. Cool.
Also amongst the winners is Petra in Jordan,
Machu Picchu in Peru, and the pyramid
in Chichen Itza in
Mexico. Wait a minute.
It also says that the Christ
Redeemer statue in Brazil,
and the Colosseum
in Rome are wonders.
I would love to go to Italy
and see the Colosseum,
stay in the middle,
like a gladiator.
Well, let's see if we can
find some cheap airfare,
and we can go towards the end of the year.
Good idea.
All right, so this list
that we gave you are
actually the new Seven
Wonders of the World.
It was voted online,
people all over the world,
that have different
candidates or different
places that were considered to be the new
Seven Wonders of the World. Among those,
like some of them that didn't win, for
example, was Angkor Wat and Cambodia.
Yeah, I never understood
that. I think Angkor
Wat is such an amazing
place and so big,
and it was the heart
of this old civilization.
Instead, we have other
things like a statue.
Yeah, yeah. I don't know
straight. But actually,
the Statue of Liberty
of the United States
was also considered as a
candidate for a wonder of the world.
Well, that's right.
America doesn't
have any wonders. You
have natural wonders, I think.
The Grand Canyon
is considered, I think,
one of the natural wonders.
Yes, and I think Niagara
Falls also would be.
But that's an interesting
point, though, Marko.
We've got the great wonders
of the world and we've
got the natural wonders.
What's the difference?
Well, natural wonder
of the world means
that it's there naturally.
It's not man-made. All of these things that
we see here, somebody had to make them.
Whereas, for example, the
Grand Canyon or Niagara Falls,
they are there
naturally. It's by nature.
All right, so man-made versus
natural or made by nature.
Right. So it's very interesting because we
said natural seven wonders of the world.
You have these, the new
ones. You have the ancient
world wonders, which
none of them are existing.
That's right. Only the
pabbles, the gardens,
the hangards of Babylon,
and the colossus sit roads.
Yeah, those ones are very
cool, but not like you said.
You can't see them
around anymore.
So, but maybe some of
you actually, maybe your
countries were considered
to host one of these
wonders or maybe you
voted for some of them.
Yeah, let us know. What is a
wonder where you come from?
It doesn't have to be on this list.
It can be something you think is wonderful.
Let us know our website is EnglishPod.com.
All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.